

Personal Information

08/17/1999, single, Brazilian Manaus, AM, Brasil +55 (92) 993897-9214 pamelasilvaoteroo@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Git Hub

Skills

React

MUI Design

VueJs

HTML5

SCSS

Responsive Layout

Git

Cypress

Sonar

Git Lab

GitHub

Jira

SQL

Python Pandas

Flagsmith

datadog

SCSS

ApexChart

Yup

Cypress

Languages

Javascript

Professional Goal

Front-end Developer

Professional Profile

I have over 5 years of experience in Software Development with a focus on Front-End Development. I have experience with React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue.js, Microfrontends, Design Systems, and end-to-end testing with Cypress for front-end. I have worked with companies ranging from retail to a multinational B2B sector company. Therefore, I am capable of building interfaces with API consumption, solving complex problems, reviewing code, making technical decisions, and proposing improvements.

Intermediary English

Employment History

Front-End Developer, Atem Distribuidora (Remote), Manaus

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- About the company: <u>Atem's Distribuidora</u> is a Brazilian company in the fuel
 distribution sector. It is one of the top 10 distributors in Brazil in terms of volume,
 according to Exame magazine.
- Creation and implementation of an internal system for the REAM Oil Refinery, using the IOC design pattern, React.js, TypeScript, and Material UI.
- Implemented improvements in the process of deploying new features using feature flags in staging and production environments.
- Version control with Git. End-to-end testing. Development of responsive interfaces based on Figma and integration with APIs using Axios.
- Creation and maintenance of front-end projects with: React.js, TypeScript, CSS, MUI Design, Yup, Apex Chart.
- Flagsmith Feature flags / Datadog Jira, Microsoft Teams, Planning Poker, Daily stand-ups, technical refinement, and sprint planning.

Mercado Eletrônico, Front End Developer (Remote), São Paulo

FEBRUARY 2022 - JANUARY 2023

- About company: Mercado Eletrônico is a multinational specializing in B2B commerce and develops automation solutions for buyers and sellers.
- Creation and maintenance of features using the **Vue.js front-end** framework with the company's internal Design System, along with **SCSS** and JavaScript.
- Participation in the Design System team, creating components used by all the front-end teams in the company.
- API integration. Microfrontends.
- Creation of tests with Cypress, using Sonar for test coverage, Jenkins, and Git/GitLab.
- Use of Jira and Microsoft Teams. Participation in technical discussions, daily stand-ups, sprint retrospectives, sprint planning, planning poker, and code reviews

Software Engineer, Benchimol, Irmãos & Cia Ltda, Manaus

MAY 2020 - FEBRUARY 2022

 About company: Bemol is the largest retail company in the Northern region of Brazil. **Typescript**

Python

С

Hobbies

Practicing martial arts, visiting tourist spots in my city, and hanging out with friends.

- I gained 3 years of experience at this company and held positions ranging from intern and Trainee Developer to Software Engineer.
- Creation and maintenance of the front-end for the Bemol Farma sales system using Vue.js, SCSS, JavaScript, and responsive interfaces.
- Development of the Landing Page for Conta Bemol in Vue.js, featuring responsive design and CSS animations.
- Back-end development: Python, Django Rest, PostgreSQL, and ABAP for SAP systems. API integration.
- Development of responsive email marketing campaigns using CSS and HTML5.
- Experience with 360° feedback, sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and technical refinement. Version control with Git.

Education

Software Engineering, Universidade Federal do Amazonas, Manaus
MARCH 2019 — DECEMBER 2024

Computer Technician, Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia do Amazonas, Manaus

FEBRUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2017

Extra-curricular activities

Campus Party CPA Amazonia, Speaker

OCTOBER 2023 - OCTOBER 2024

On October 13th, I gave a talk on "Design System: When to Implement It" at Campus Party Brasil, CPAmazonia edition, hosted by the Pyladies community.

Courses

Introduction to Observability, Datadog

JULY 2024 - JULY 2024

Datadog Quick Start, Datadog

JULY 2024 - JULY 2024

Datadog Foundation, Datadog

JULY 2024 - JULY 2024

API with Django 3: Django Rest Framework, Alura

DECEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

HTML5 and CSS3 Part 4: Advancing in CSS

MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2021

JavaScript: getting started with the language, Alura

OCTOBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Communication: How to Express Yourself Clearly and Be Understood, Alura

FEBRUARY 2021 - FEBRUARY 2021